momgenerations.com 2008-12-20

# None

### Privacy Policy

Updated on March 12, 2008

**Introduction:** At Mom Generations, LLC we realize the importance of feeling safe online and are fully committed to ensuring that your privacy is respected and protected. Our Privacy Policy below outlines the type of information we collect and receive from you while you are within the Mom Generations Network, as well as ways in which we process and, sometimes, share such information and how you can correct or change such information. The Mom Generations Network is defined as the network of websites and services that are owned and operated by Mom Generations, LLC and its subsidiaries. Each site included within the Mom Generations Network is governed by this Privacy Policy unless otherwise noted on such site.

**PLEASE REVIEW THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND THE TERMS OF SERVICE FOR THE Mom Generations NETWORK CAREFULLY. YOUR USE OF THIS SITE SIGNIFIES YOUR AGREEMENT TO SUCH PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF SERVICE.SUCH PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF SERVICE.**

  1. How Mom Generations Collects Information 
    * Personal Data you provide 
    * Information Mom Generations collects
  2. Our Use of Your Information 
  3. Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information to Third Parties 
  4. Mom Generations Opt-in/Opt-out Policy 
  5. Third Party Advertising and Links to other Sites. 
  6. Access and Correction 
  7. Guidelines regarding children 
  8. Public forums/chat rooms/message boards/bulletin boards/social networking 
  9. How we protect and secure your information 
  10. Applicable Law 
  11. Changes to this Privacy Policy 
  12. Contact Information

**1\. How Mom Generations Collects Information**   
A. Personal Data you provide to Mom Generations

Personally Identifiable Information is any information that can be used to identify a specific individual such as your name, email address, home address, and phone number. Mom Generations asks you to provide Personally Identifiable Information in various places throughout the Mom Generations Network. Some of these areas where the collection of such information takes place are listed below:

_Member Registration_   
Some Mom Generations' features, tools and services may require you to register to become a member. During this member registration process, we will ask you for Personally Identifiable Information. In addition, you may choose to provide Mom Generations with additional information including marital status, household income, education and employment status. 

_Email Newsletters_   
Mom Generations offers electronic newsletters on a variety of topics. If you subscribe to any of these newsletters, you will be required to provide a valid email address as well as any other information that is relevant to the delivery of the newsletter. 

_Surveys and Polls_   
Mom Generations offer online surveys and questionnaires that ask users for opinions on various issues and/or other information. Occasionally, we may request demographic information (like zip code, age or gender) when you answer a survey. Such surveys are completely voluntary.

_Sweepstakes and Contests_   
Mom Generations regularly operate sweepstakes, contests and giveaways throughout the Mom Generations Network. We typically ask you for your email address and/or phone number (to notify you if you've won, or not). We also ask for first and last names, and sometimes post office addresses in order to verify the entrant's identity. In some situations, we need additional information as part of the entry process, such as a prize selection choice. 

_ECommerce Transactions_   
When you engage in an ecommerce transaction on the Mom Generations Network you may be asked to provide credit card information and other Personally Identifiable Information in order to complete the transaction. 

B. Information gathered by Mom Generations and its third party service providers 

When you visit the Mom Generations Network and interact with the services and tools that reside there, Mom Generations and third parties with whom Mom Generations has contracted to provide services to Mom Generations may collect information on your actions. This type of information is generally collected from two sources. One is from the server log files and the other is from cookies. 

  * _IP Address_

Your IP address is a number that is assigned by your ISP (Internet Service Provider) to your computer to identify its location. We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website. We also sometimes use IP addresses to communicate with members and subscribers and possibly even ban those members who are not complying with our [Terms of Service](http://www.ivillage.com/about/0,,qr4p,00.html).    

  * _Cookies_

Our site uses a feature of your browser to set a "cookie" on your computer. Cookies are small packets of information that a site's computer stores on your computer. The Mom Generations Network can then read the cookies whenever you visit the Mom Generations websites. We use cookies to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site, to deliver content specific to your interests, to track the pages you've visited and to make sure you don't see the same ads repeatedly. These cookies allow us to use the information we collect to customize your Mom Generations experience so that your visit to Mom Generations is as relevant and as valuable to you as possible. 

You may modify your browser preference to provide you with choices relating to cookies. You have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject cookies you may be unable to use those Mom Generations services that require registration in order to participate or will have to sign in each time you visit the Mom Generations Network. 

**2\. How Mom Generations uses Information it collects**

Mom Generations uses the information you provide for several purposes, such as to communicate with you and to give you a better experience when visiting the Mom Generations Network by personalizing tools, content, services and email messages. Mom Generations also uses this information to build new services and develop offers that Mom Generations believes are more relevant and valuable to you. 

The information collected by Mom Generations is also used to create aggregated portraits of the Mom Generations audience, portraits which present anonymous statistical demographic information but no personally identifiable information. This aggregated information is used, among other things, to determine trends and needs, and also to supply market research to potential advertisers and partners to help them understand who the Mom Generations audience is. For example, we may create a report that tells advertisers that 60 percent of our members are females in a certain age range, so that they can determine which of their products or services are most appropriate for our members. 

Mom Generations offers the ability to forward an article to another person via email. If you use this service, we will use the recipient's email address in order to send the article or postcard and we will also ask for your email address. We do not use the recipient's email address for any other purpose unless such recipient gives us permission to do so.

**3\. Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information to Third Parties**

Mom Generations does not sell or otherwise share Personally Identifiable Information with unaffiliated third parties without your consent (please see the Opt-In/Opt-Out Policy below), except in the following instances: (i) disclosure is required by applicable law or pursuant to a court or similar order; (ii) as deemed necessary, in Mom Generations's discretion, to protect the legal rights or the property of Mom Generations, a member or third party, or to prevent personal injury; and/or (iii) in the event of a sale, merger, assignment, joint venture or other transfer or disposition of a portion or all of the assets or stock of Mom Generations or its affiliated entities (including, without limitation, in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings). In addition, Mom Generations may provide Personally Identifiable Information to third parties who are providing technical or fulfillment services on behalf of Mom Generations when such disclosure is required in order to provide those services, provided that such third parties agree to be bound by Mom Generations's Privacy Policy. Mom Generations also reserves the right to share any Personally Identifiable Information or other information about you which you provide to (or which is gathered from) the Mom Generations Network with any or all of its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, our "Affiliates") (subject to the opt-out right described below, with respect to disclosures of Personally Identifiable Information to Affiliates for their direct marketing uses). Mom Generations will also have access to any information you provide to (or which is gathered from) the web sites of any of our Affiliates. 

Frequently, sweepstakes and contests offered on the Mom Generations Network are sponsored by unaffiliated third parties. Information that you provide as part of an entry into a sponsored sweepstakes or contest will be shared with the sponsor if we advise you of such in the sweepstakes rules. Most sweepstakes and contests will also ask you to consent to the release of information contained within the entry form for tax purposes if you become a winner. You should carefully review the rules of each sweepstakes, contest and giveaway which you enter as they may contain additional important information about Mom Generations' or a sponsor's use of your personally identifiable information. The information you provide on pages of the Mom Generations Network that are co-branded with a third party (including tools that are hosted by a third party) may be shared with advertisers and partners on an aggregated basis and in these instances your permission will not be requested since no Personally Identifiable Information will be shared or provided to these third party sponsors or advertisers. Mom Generations will, however, use commercially reasonable efforts to contractually require all such third party advertisers and partners to agree not to use any non-personally identifiable information about you, in conjunction with other sources of information, or otherwise, to identify you. 

**4\. The Mom Generations Opt-in/Opt-out Policy**

Upon registration or from time-to-time, you may be asked to indicate whether you are interested in receiving information from us about special offers or news about our sites and advertisers. If you do choose to receive these communications by means of an opt-in, we will occasionally send you an email message that matches your request(s). We currently provide the following opt-out opportunities: 

  1. At any time, you can follow a link provided in every newsletter or email message (except for e-commerce confirmation or service notice emails) to unsubscribe from that mailing list or email service. 
  2. At any time, you can contact us through [customerservice@momgenerations.com](mailto:customerservice@momgenerations.com) to have your contact preference changed to "Do Not Contact Me." 
  3. Notwithstanding anything else in this Privacy Policy, please note that Mom Generations reserves the right to contact you in the event of a change in the Mom Generations Terms of Service and/or this Privacy Policy. 
  4. At any time, you can [_opt out_](http://visitor.constantcontact.com/d.jsp?v=001dRCypZS7HoUyuzd_bc97bCvt_b-2M5PtgwEuv1a7l7-b__nUil-FOplIAP0G3yHbW13GfGwXqWM%3D&p=un) of having your Personally Identifiable Information shared with our Affiliates for their direct marketing purposes. 

You will also be provided with the opportunity to opt-in to receive offers, goods and services directly from select companies other than Mom Generations. In such instances where you have opted-in to receive such offers, goods and services from third parties, Mom Generations will share your information with such third parties and will often provide you access to the Privacy Policy of the third party for your review via a link. In some instances, when you have the opportunity on the Mom Generations Network to subscribe to a newsletter offered by a third-party email service or advertiser or partner, the email address information will be located on the third party's server and any information you provide is subject to that entity's Privacy Policy, not this one. 

If you have additional questions about how one of our advertisers, partners or sponsors use information about you, we urge you to contact them directly. For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "opt-in" is generally defined as any affirmative action by a Mom Generations member or visitor to submit or receive information, as the case may be.

**5\. Third Party Advertising and Links to other Sites.**

The Mom Generations Network contains links to advertiser and partner websites that are not co-branded or affiliated with Mom Generations in any way. We cannot be responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such non-Mom Generations websites, and we do not control the practices of any of our advertisers or partners to whose sites we link. 

**6\. Access and Correction**

Mom Generations provides you with the ability to access, correct or change the Personally Identifiable Information in your member portrait at any time, including contact information or other information you've provided to us. However, you cannot currently change your member name although you may re-register and choose a new name. To review, modify or delete your member information, please _click here_. Please be advised that Mom Generations currently archives information it collects on its members and visitors. 

**7\. Guidelines regarding children**

Personal information about children is a concern for all of us. At Mom Generations, we take the protection of children's privacy very seriously. Mom Generations does not encourage participation or visitation by children. Visitors who are known to be under the age of 13 are prohibited from becoming a member. Anyone under the age of eighteen is discouraged from participating in any sex related chats or message boards and we ask that no one less than eighteen years of age become a community volunteer. 

**8\. Public forums/chat rooms/message boards/bulletin boards/social networking**

Throughout the Mom Generations Network various public forums such as chat rooms, message boards, and various question and answer areas are available to you as a registered Mom Generations member. 

Please remember that any information you disclose in these public forum areas becomes public information and is immediately accessible on the Mom Generations Network, so it is important for you to exercise discretion and appropriate caution when deciding to reveal personal information in these areas. Mom Generations may decide to utilize the content of Q&A's, interactions with experts, and/or chat room and message board content throughout the Mom Generations Network and in promotions in order to enhance Mom Generations ' editorial, advertising, promotional and similar activities. In those cases, we often provide authorship credit by listing the author's member name. We therefore encourage you to use care in protecting your identity when you choose a member name and to keep your member name confidential. 

**9\. How we protect and secure your information**

Mom Generations has numerous security measures in place to protect you from the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control, including your credit card information if you choose to conduct an e-commerce transaction on the Mom Generations Network. All of your member information requires use of your password. We recommend that you do not share your password with anyone. Mom Generations uses industry-standard tools, such as firewalls, to ensure that your information is secure and confidential. 

**10\. Applicable Law**

We control and operate the Mom Generations Network from the United States. The Mom Generations Network is not intended to subject us to the laws or jurisdiction of any state, country or territory other than that of the United States. Please note that we do not represent or warrant that the Mom Generations Network is appropriate for use in any particular jurisdiction. Those who choose to access the Mom Generations Network do so at their own initiative and are responsible for complying with all local laws, rules and regulations.

**11\. Changes to this Privacy Policy** We will notify our members when we make any significant changes to our Privacy Policy that affect the use of any personally identifiable information we collect. We will not make new use of any Personally Identifiable Information which Mom Generations gathered from individual members or visitors prior to any such significant change in our Privacy Policy without first obtaining the member's or visitor's consent for any new uses. In instances where we ask for your Personally Identifiable Information and we tell you the data we are collecting on that page will be shared with unaffiliated third parties, and in cases where a member, visitor or subscriber to the Mom Generations Network opts-in to share his/her information with third parties, those disclosures and opt-ins will override anything to the contrary in this Privacy Policy. In addition, Mom Generations reserves the right to make non-significant changes to our Privacy Policy that will not affect Mom Generations' use of a user's Personally Identifiable Information at any time without any notice to you other than posting any such changes in a revised Privacy Policy on the Mom Generations Network. We encourage you to periodically review our Privacy Policy to be sure you are familiar with the most current version. The Privacy Policy will include the most recent date in which any revision has been made. Please note that this Privacy Policy is also incorporated into Mom Generations' Terms of Service. 

**12\. Contact information** If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or anything else about Mom Generations, you can contact us at the following email address: [customerservice@momgenerations.com](mailto:customerservice@momgenerations.com)
